Guide to the Hart, Schaffner & Marx Advertising Service materials, 1937-1964 and undated RL.11494
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hart, Schaffner & Marx Advertising Service materials
1937-1964 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hart, Schaffner & Marx
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11494
10.0 Linear Feet
Chicago, Ill. based manufacturer of mens clothing. Collection includes Advertising Service packages of promotional and advertising designs and campaign suggestions by season; summaries of promotional campaigns; mounted logos including one by Robert Reinhardt von Liski and other materials that document marketing efforts by Hart Schaffner & Marx. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabeticically.
Biographical / Historical
Chicago-based manufacturer of men's clothing. Founded as Harry Hart and Brother in 1872 by Harry and Max Hart. Renamed Hart, Abt and Marx 1879; Hart, Schaffner & Marx 1887. Shifted focus from retail to wholesale clothing manufacture; first national advertising 1897. Incorporated 1911. Reorganized as a holding company, Hartmarx Corporation, 1983. Filed bankruptcy 2009. Acquired by Authentic Brands Group 2012.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Hart, Schaffner & Marx Advertising Service materials were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2017.
Related Materials
Related may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Gary and Sandra Baden Collection of Print Advertisements; Garrett Orr papers; General Outdoor Advertising Company Plan Books; Henry Haberman papers; J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements collection; J. Walter Thompson Company New Business records; Roy Lightner collection of antique advertisements
Collection Overview
Includes Advertising Service packages of promotional and advertising designs and campaign suggestions by season; summaries of promotional campaigns; mounted logos including one by Robert Reinhardt von Liski and other materials that document men's clothing marketing efforts by Hart Schaffner & Marx. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Clothing and dress; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1948-1952 (Box 1)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1955-1957 (Box 4)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1958-1960 (Box 6)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1960-1961 (Box 8)
- Advertising Service campaign materials, 1962-1964 (Box 9)
- Havana Holiday campaign, 1958 (Box 10)
- Logo, mounted copper engraving, undated (Box 10)
- Logo, Robert Reinhardt von Liski, undated (Box 10)
- Newspaper advertising, 1950-1956 (Box 10)
- Six Honeys promotional guide, 1937 (Box 10)